故事始于2010年，那会儿的网络论坛间可谓是“仇”深似海
The year is 2010 and the vendetta between internet forums is at an all time high.
汤不热（Tumblr）被当场抓包偷梗，还恬不知耻地据为己有
Tumblr is caught stealing memes and claiming them as their own,
此举彻底点燃了4chan用户的无名业火
which absolutely enrages the users on 4chan.
也不知汤不热是真傻还是装蒜
Whether or not Tumblr realizes it,
他们已然犯下了网络世界最“大逆不道”的滔天原罪
they have just committed the unholiest of internet sins.
而这一举动，也点燃了这些论坛有史以来最盛大战争的导火索
And with it, they spark the biggest declaration of war these boards have ever seen.
从汤不热用户被戳中G点，到大规模网络攻击
From Tumblr users getting triggered, to massive cyber attacks,
到4chan用全网最“辣眼睛”的图片刷屏
to 4chan spamming pictures of the most heinous things on the internet,
甚至还催生了一段奇妙姻缘
to even an unlikely romance.
可以毫不夸张地说，这是互联网史上最恢弘的战役之一
This is quite literally one of the biggest battles the internet has ever seen.
这，就是4chan大战汤不热的传奇故事
This is the legendary story of 4chan vs Tumblr.
2007年，4chan最古早的梗之一横空出世
In 2007, one of 4chan's most ancient memes was born,
描绘了一位老大爷心脏病发，口中念着那句传奇的HNNG
depicting an old man having a heart attack, and saying the legendary HNNG.
果不其然，这个梗迅速走红
Of course, this meme became widely popular,
最终传遍了互联网的犄角旮旯，一如4chan的诸多“大作”
and was eventually used all over the internet, much like many other of 4chan's creations.
然而，汤不热正在暗处视奸
However, Tumblr was watching from the shadows,
他们对4chan誉满全球的影响力早已垂涎三尺
and they began to grow jealous of 4chan's impact around the world.
于是乎，一位用户提出了个胆大包天的计划
So one user proposed a daring plan,
那就是窃取4chan的神圣梗HNNG，再把它重塑为汤不热的“独家记忆”
to forge a meme by stealing 4chan's sacred HNNG, and reshaping it into something Tumblr could call its own.
汤不热首偷，再偷必究
汤不热的用户们对这个新梗赞不绝口
This new meme was thought to be absolutely brilliant by users on Tumblr,
自诩为神来之笔，还坚信这将颠覆整个网络文化史
and they believed it would change internet culture forever.
好了，它来了
Okay, here it is.
他们发明了一个词组，what is air
They came up with the term, what is air?
用来形容某人笑到窒息，连呼吸都给忘了
Referring to someone laughing so hard that they just forget to breathe.
汤不热的用户们对此趋之若鹜
Users on Tumblr were obsessed,
随后更将其作为内部黑话在其他论坛里疯狂刷屏
later using it on other forums as an inside joke.
当汤不热远征Omegle时
The term spread worse than the plague,
这个词组的传播速度堪比瘟疫，聊天室里被这个梗刷了个底朝天
when Tumblr raids Omegle, where they flood the chat rooms with the meme.
只要一个用户说出，what is air
One user would say, what is air?
通话双方就会立马甩出汤不热的链接，以此证明彼此都“懂这个梗”
And both callers would quickly send a link to Tumblr, showing each other that they were familiar with the joke.
段友出征，寸草不生说是
当然，Omegle上的许多用户看得是一头雾水
Of course, many users going on Omegle were confused,
而大多数搞懂了的人，也完全get不到笑点在哪
and most of those who caught on, didn't think it was funny at all.
但汤不热自己却爱得深沉
But Tumblr absolutely loved it.
彼时，没人能逃离汤不热的巨魔行径
At this point in time, no one can escape Tumblr's trolling,
what is air这个词仿佛被刷得到处都是
and it seems like the term, what is air? is getting spammed everywhere.
但这还不是全部，为了明目张胆地岁月史书
But that's not all. In a blatant attempt to rewrite history,
这个梗还被添加到了城市词典
the meme is added to the Urban Dictionary.
词条的释义竟暗示HNNG这个词，实际上归汤不热所有
With the entry implying that the term, HNNG, actually belongs to Tumblr.
因此，what is air这个梗，正式演变成了一场
The what is air meme, therefore, officially became a power grab
旨在取代HNNG的“夺权行动”
to become HNNG's new replacement.
这一切让4chan怒不可遏
All of this got 4chan beyond furious.
不仅是因为HNNG是他们的原创，还因为汤不热这个新梗简直尬出天际
Not only was HNNG their term, but Tumblr's new meme wasn't even funny.
最重要的是，搞远征突袭的明明是4chan，而不是汤不热
On top of that, 4chan was the one who conducted raids, not Tumblr.
于是，在2010年11月4日，4chan发帖，宣告“霸王行动”正式启动
So on November 4th, 2010, 4chan makes a post, declaring Operation Overlord.
此举显然是在致敬二战时期的诺曼底登陆战役
A nod to the Battle of Normandy Beach in World War 2.
计划通俗易懂
The plan is simple.
正如其名，4chan将悄然备战，直捣汤不热的“海滩”
Following its namesake, 4chan would quietly prepare to rush the beaches of Tumblr,
创建新账户并尽可能多地批量关注用户
making new accounts and mass following as many users as possible.
只要运气够好，许多汤不热用户就会回关他们
If they are lucky, many of the Tumblr users would follow them back,
这意味着这些4chan用户发的任何帖子，都会出现在对方的时间线上
meaning that they would be able to see whatever these 4chan users post.
与此同时，如同空降师深入敌后
Meanwhile, similar to the Airborne Division dropping behind enemy lines,
4chan的“特种部队”将黑入汤不热的一些头部大号
4chan Special Forces would hack into some of Tumblr's biggest accounts,
缓慢而坚定地，接管这个网站
slowly but surely taking over the site.
这样的行动将持续好几天
This would repeat for the next few days.
而在此期间，黑客们早已囤积了网上能搜罗到的最丧心病狂的玩意儿
All while, the hackers stockpiled some of the most heinous things they could find on the internet,
兴奋地等待着发起总攻的绝佳时机
excitedly waiting for the perfect moment to launch their attack.
随后，时机成熟
Then, it happened.
4chan用那些病入膏肓的网虫
4chan spams Tumblr with the worst things
所能想象出的最不堪入目的内容，对汤不热进行了地毯式轰炸
that the chronically online mind could ever conceive of.
这简直避无可避
It's inescapable.
每出现一个正常的帖子，就有十张更辣眼睛的图片取而代之
For every real post, 10 more disturbing pictures take its place.
全世界的汤不热用户都遭受了精神暴击
Tumblr users from around the world are traumatized,
无数画面在他们的记忆里刻下了永久的烙印
with many of the images ingrained in their memory.
混乱持续不断，直到第四天
The chaos continues until, on the fourth day,
4chan开始盘算着按下那个“红色按钮”
4chan contemplates pressing the big red button.
11月14日，一位匿名用户发布了他们最后阶段的计划
November 14th, an anonymous user posts their plans for the last phase
这盘大棋终于要收官了
that is finally coming to fruition.
给予汤不热致命一击的时刻已到，是时候让这个网站彻底宕机了
The time comes for the killing blow against Tumblr to take the site completely offline.
在这个帖子发布后，留给汤不热安全团队的准备时间已经不多了
After this post goes live, there isn't much time for the Tumblr security team to prepare.
下午5点准时到来，全球的4chan用户合力发动了一场大规模DDoS攻击
5pm comes quickly, and 4chan users from across the globe combine their efforts in a massive DDoS attack,
如惊涛骇浪般席卷了汤不热
which comes crashing down on Tumblr, like a tsunami.
网站最终还是宕机了
The site eventually goes down.
然而，尽管主页已经无法访问，但大多数个人博客却幸免于难
However, even though the main page is unreachable, most of the individual blogs survive.
很明显，汤不热依然坚挺，但他们必须得狠狠地“回敬”4chan
It's clear that though Tumblr remains strong, they need to get 4chan back.
于是，“萌猫行动”应运而生
Thus, Operation Overkitten is born.
他们开始在4chan上疯狂刷屏可爱的猫咪图片，以及那句，what is air
They begin spamming cute pictures of cats, and the phrase, what is air, all over 4chan.
但这只招致了更多的混乱
But this just brings more chaos.
4chan用户在汤不热被大规模封禁，反之亦然
4chan users get mass banned on Tumblr, and vice versa.
很快，4chan的管理员也介入了
Soon, the 4chan mods get involved.
他们暂时关闭了发帖权限
They temporarily take away the ability to make threads.
但随着“霸王行动”的落幕
But as the doors close on Operation Overlord,
事情……开始朝着一个诡异又“魅惑”的方向急转直下
things take a weirdly... seductive turn.
4chan和汤不热双方的用户突然意识到
Users on both 4chan and Tumblr realize
他们彼此间的共同点，远比之前想象的要多
that they have more in common with one another than they had previously thought.
这种浪漫的“张力”不断升温，直到一位汤不热用户
This romantic tension rose until one Tumblr user
终于提出了一个最“火辣”的提议
finally proposes a most steamy idea.
“与其打打杀杀，不如‘为爱鼓掌’”
Instead of fighting each other, why don't they just make love?
这条评论瞬间点燃了有史以来最离奇的“同人创作”之火
This single comment sparks one of the most bizarre fanfics ever written.
也确实是互联网上最诡异的奇观之一
And truly, one of the strangest things on the internet.
这对神仙眷侣后来被称为Fort Tumblr
This power couple would come to be known as Fort Tumblr.
爱音（误）酱爱音酱，What is air？
Anon! Hey, Anon! What is air?
空气（消歧义）
Air, disambiguation.
空气是地球大气层的一部分，人类赖以呼吸
Air is part of the earth's atmosphere that humans breathe.
它由78%的氮气，31%（？）的氧气和1%的地球（？）组成
It's made up of 78% nitrogen, 31% oxygen, and 1% of Earth.
歌曲，AIR。炭疽乐队的一首歌曲... Air
Songs, AIR. A song by anthrax from spreading the disease. Air.
4chan上的许多用户出人意料地上了这艘贼船
Many users on 4chan are surprisingly on board.
在随后的几周里，无数相关的帖子被创建出来
And in the following weeks, countless threads are created.
描绘了两个网站拟人化后的艺术作品、漫画、卡通形象的互动
Depicting artwork, comics, cartoon versions of the sites interacting with each other,
甚至还有一些本视频无法展示的内容
and even some stuff that we can't show in this video.
许多帖子很快就转变成了汤不热和4chan用户“水乳交融”的圣地
Many threads soon transform into a place where both Tumblr and 4chan users can intermingle.
哥们儿，4chan这波可是血赚了
And boy, was 4chan rewarded.
4chan甚至创建了科普贴，以便汤不热用户学习他们的行话
4chan even creates info threads so that Tumblr could learn their lingo.
双方组织了线下见面会，一些4chan用户显然得吃了
Meetups are organized, and some 4chan users apparently get lucky.
另一位匿名用户居然真的向一位汤不热用户求婚了
Another anon actually proposes to one of the Tumblr users.
而在所有人震惊的目光中，她说了“我愿意”
And to everyone's shock, she says yes.
这场战争已悄然演变成一个盛大的爱情故事
The war has slowly evolved into a massive love story.
4chan和汤不热双方都一致认为，这样皆大欢喜
With both 4chan and Tumblr agreeing that it is better this way.
就像这样，二人幸终，共同走向了夕阳
And just like that, everyone walks into the sunset together as one.
他们找到了自己的“第九天堂”，他们的“极乐世界”
They have found their Cloud 9, their Nirvana,
剩下的只有和平与爱
and nothing but peace and love remain.
但我们的故事还远未结束
But our story isn't over just quite yet.
毕竟，爱情总不会天长地久
After all, love doesn't always last forever.
许多年过去了，“霸王行动”也逐渐风化成了互联网的民间传说
Many years pass, and Operation Overlord fades into internet folklore.
尽管那场大战早已鸣金收兵，但4chan上的一位用户却开始追忆似水年华
Though the Great War has long since been over, one user on 4chan reminisces about the past.
这天是美利坚的独立日
It is Independence Day in the US of A,
当大多数美国人都在外面放烟花时
and while most Americans are out lighting fireworks,
他觉得这是个重温峥嵘岁月的绝佳机会
he figures this is the perfect opportunity to relive the good old days.
于是他策划了一个“妙计”
So he hatches a plan.
他潜入汤不热，伪装成他们的一员，并创建了一个帖子，向4chan“宣战”
He infiltrates Tumblr, posing as one of their own, and creates a thread declaring war on 4chan.
他在帖子中声称，4chan上充斥着这个星球上最种族主义
In his post, he claims that 4chan is filled with the most racist,
最厌恶女性、最纯粹邪恶的人
misogynistic, and pure evil people on the planet.
他发起了“#关停4chan”运动，并试图让汤不热的用户们上钩
He begins the movement, # shut down 4chan, and attempts to get Tumblr on board.
他自认为这个帖子“堪称绝妙”，并且很快就火了起来
He believes this post is brilliant, and it quickly picks up steam.
然而，汤不热上的许多用户一眼就看穿了他
However, many users on Tumblr see right through him,
意识到这个帖子不过是钩直饵咸
and realize that this thread is nothing but low quality bait.
尽管如此，雪球还是越滚越大
Even still, the snowball keeps rolling,
因为更多激情澎湃的汤不热用户觉得，他们有责任
as more passionate Tumblr users feel the responsibility
净化互联网，将4chan扫地出门
to cleanse the internet of 4chan.
任务无比清晰
The mission is crystal clear.
制造足够大的噪音，让4chan彻底关站，一劳永逸地结束他们的混乱
Make enough noise to shut down 4chan for good, and put an end to their chaos once and for all.
汤不热用户打响了第一枪，他们开始在4chan上发布自己的帖子
Tumblr users fire their first shots, and begin making their own posts on 4chan.
帖子的猛攻接踵而至，但4chan的版主们早已准备就绪
The onslaught of threads keep coming, but the 4chan moderators are at the ready,
迅速封禁任何来犯的汤不热帖子
swiftly banning any Tumblr post coming in.
然后，一个自称来自“匿名者”的帖子出现了
Then, a thread appeared from none other than Anonymous,
声称他们已经反水，现在正帮助汤不热扳倒4chan
claiming that they had turned on 4chan, and were now helping Tumblr take them down.
但这个诡计并没持续多久。4chan立即识破这是假货
But the ruse didn't last long. 4chan immediately recognized it as a fake.
归根结底，这只是一个汤不热用户试图恐吓他们一下
And in the end, it was just a Tumblr user, trying to give them a scare.
汤不热以请愿作为反击
Tumblr fired back with a petition,
要求4chan用户为他们的网络罪行承担责任
demanding that 4chan users be held accountable for their internet crimes.
但4chan对此只能嗤之以鼻
But 4chan could only laugh.
人人都知道请愿根本毫无卵用
Everyone knew petitions went nowhere.
以至于无数匿名用户自己也去签了名，纯粹是为了起哄
So much so, that countless anons signed it themselves, just for the joke.
如果这还不够，4chan还加倍下注
If that wasn't enough, 4chan doubled down,
发起了自己的反请愿，将汤不热用户标记为“无能的肥仔”
and launched their own counter-petition, labeling Tumblr users as disabled landwhales.
笑点解析：landwhales在俚语里有肥仔的意思
而这个反请愿只用了一半的时间，就获得了十倍的签名量
And it racked up 10 times the signatures in half the time.
到了这个地步，汤不热的用户们开始意识到自己的错误，但一切都太晚了
At this point, users on Tumblr began to realize their mistake, but it is already too late.
随之而来的，是堪比凝固汽油弹的数字轰炸
What followed was the digital equivalent of Napalm.
汤不热的信息流被淹没了
Tumblr feeds flooded,
充斥着互联网所能产生的最令人震惊、最令人作呕的内容
with some of the most shocking, revolting content the internet could produce.
刷汤不热的体验，瞬间演变成了一场恐怖表演
Scrolling Tumblr instantly evolved into a horror show.
因此，为了屏蔽4chan，汤不热迅速制作了一份定向标签黑名单
So in an attempt to block 4chan, Tumblr quickly makes a list of targeted tags.
但显而易见，这并没什么用
But of course, it doesn't help much.
有些人甚至还上传了他们挣扎实录的视频
Some even post videos of their struggles.
现在发生的是，呃……
What's happening is, um...
他们决定开始在标签里发布“引战”和“刺激性”的东西
They decided to start posting and triggering things in the tags
来激怒人们，让他们抓狂
to trigger people and make them freak out.
他们觉得这超级搞笑
They think it's absolutely hilarious.
但实际上这真的一团糟
It's actually really messed up.
即使面临失败，汤不热也不想不战而降
Even facing defeat, Tumblr didn't want to go down without a fight.
于是他们想出了一个异想天开的主意
So they came up with an outlandish idea.
为了淹没这场大屠杀，抵御4chan的入侵者
In order to drown out the carnage and fend off the fortune invaders,
他们决定用自己的自拍照来刷爆标签
they would spam the tags with their own selfies.
这样一来，任何访问该网站的人，都会被他们汤不热同志们的照片所迎接
So that anyone visiting the site would be greeted with pictures of their fellow Tumblr conrads.
但4chan简直爱死这个了
But 4chan loved this.
他们瞬间就适应了，拿着那些自拍照，把它们扭曲成限制级的梗图
They adapted instantly, taking those very selfies, distorting them into x-rated memes,
再狠狠地扔回了战壕
and hurling them back into the trenches.
其他汤不热用户试图用一波波的萌图来反击
Other Tumblr users tried to counter with waves of cute pictures.
但在这一点上，4chan早已造成了太多的伤害
But at this point, 4chan had already done too much damage.
因此，作为背水一战
So in a last ditch effort to fight back,
汤不热用户开始发布教程，指导大家如何直接反击4chan
Tumblr users began posting instructions on how to fight 4chan directly.
这很简单
It was easy.
他们所要做的就是在浏览器中打开4chan
All they had to do was open up 4chan in their browser,
在记事本中键入命令，包括一些关于删除system 32的内容
type commands in a notepad, including something about deleting system 32,
然后将该文件保存到他们的计算机上
then save the file to their computer.
一旦他们这样做了
Once they did that,
他们就应该能看到4chan上所有发帖者的位置
they should be able to see the location of all the posters on 4chan,
然后他们就可以向FBI举报了
which they could then report to the FBI.
但毫无疑问，刷屏这些教程的账户，只是4chan安插的卧底
But of course, the accounts spamming these instructions were just undercover 4chan users.
而等到那些技术宅汤不热用户警告大家时，为时已晚
And by the time the text-savvy Tumblr users could warn everyone, it was already too late.
许多汤不热用户已经删除了system 32，使他们的电脑完全报废
Many users on Tumblr had already deleted system 32, making their computers completely unusable.
然而，汤不热拒绝放弃，一些用户
However, Tumblr refused to give up, and some users
起草了已知的4chan入侵者的公开黑名单，希望借此吓退他们
drafted public blocklists of known 4chan raiders, hoping that they could scare them off.
但这样做，他们也暴露了自己的电子邮件地址
But by doing this, they revealed their email addresses.
很快，他们的收件箱就被各种恐怖事物给轰炸了
Quickly, their inboxes were firebombed with horrors.
他们甚至被订阅了人类已知的所有垃圾邮件
And they were even signed up for every spam email known to mankind.
试图警告他人的尝试也遭到了同样可怕的反噬
Attempts to warn others backfired just as terribly.
一个女孩上传了一段视频，恳求人们远离4chan
One girl uploaded a video begging people to stay away from 4chan.
几小时内，视频就被删除了
Within hours, it was deleted.
她的家被围攻了，堆满了恶作剧的外卖披萨、垃圾邮件和各种恐吓电话
Her home was besieged, with prank delivery pizzas, junk mail, and frightening calls.
到了这个地步，很明显4chan赢了，但最终结果是毁灭性的
At this point, it was clear that 4chan had won, but the end results were devastating.
到处都是精神创伤、PTSD和情感崩溃的呼喊
There were cries of trauma, PTSD, and emotional devastation.
许多用户被迫暂别汤不热很长一段时间，直到混乱平息
Many of the users were forced to take a long break from Tumblr until the chaos dies down.
4chan庆祝着他们毫无悬念的胜利
4chan celebrates its clear victory,
而那个独自发动了这场战争的用户意识到，他欣赏到了一场毕生难忘的大秀
and the sole user who started the war realized he got a show of a lifetime.
而这一切，都是他在他舒适的家中运筹帷幄
All from the comfort of his own home.